

Ruben Caliandro

Technical Director, Graphics and Game Programmer

Date of Birth June 7, 1990

Email ruben.caliandro@gmail.com

Phone (+39) 333 736 8333

Location Torino, IT

Github https://github.com/chosko

PROFILES Linkedin https://www.linkedin.com/in/rubencaliandro/en

Personal https://chosko.com

I work as Technical Director at Tiny Bull Studios, an indie game developer based in Torino (Italy). I work since 2016 in the video game industry and I have 10+ years of former experience as hobbyist in Game Programming and Graphics Programming.

ABOUT I coded my first Graphics framework based on DirectX at the age of 15-17 and my greatest passion since then is shader programming. I also worked as Web Developer from 2010 to 2016, in companies located in Italy (Torino) and USA (Sunnyvale, CA).

I graduated with a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science in 2012 and a Master's Degree in Virtual Reality in 2017, both with the score of 110/110 with honors.

Work Experience

♥ TURIN, ITALY

CONTACT

🛗 SEP, 2020 — PRESENT

① 1 YEAR 3 MONTHS

Technical Director at Tiny Bull Studios srl:

Technical Art Direction, R&D and team management

- Researching state-of-art production and rendering techniques for specific types of game content, with an eye on CPU and GPU optimisation in advance
- Defining optimised workflows for creating and implementing game art in a feasible way for a small team of Artists
- Giving technical instructions to Artists and mentoring to Technical Artists
- Programming tools in support of art production workflows
- Shader programming
- Main Technologies: Nintendo Switch, Unity, C#, ShaderLab, CG/HLSL/GLSL

 \colongraph Turin, Italy

 $\stackrel{\text{def}}{=}$ Dec, 2016 — Aug, 2020

O 3 YEARS 8 MONTHS

Graphics Programmer, Game Programmer at Tiny Bull Studios srl:

Visual Effects and Game Programming

- Shader Programming and Optimisation
- Particle Systems and Post-Processing
- Making the effects support Virtual Reality
- Main Technologies: Unity, C#, ShaderLab, CG/HLSL/GLSL, Oculus, Vive, PlayStation 4

♥ TURIN, ITALY - SUNNYVALE, USA

[™] APR, 2010 — SEP, 2017

O 7 YEARS 5 MONTHS

Full-stack Web Developer at various companies:

Full-stack Web Development

- Main technologies: Node/Express, Ruby/Rails, Angular, AWS, Docker, Databases, PHP
- More about the companies on LinkedIn

VOLUNTEER

₩ SEP, 2009 — JUN, 2013

① 3 YEARS 9 MONTHS

Film Projectionist, Cinema Teatro Cuore:

35mm Film Projections.

- Film assembling and deassembling, security checks, film projections

EDUCATION

₩ JAN, 2013 — OCT, 2017

Score: 110/110 with honors

₩ SEP, 2009 — DEC, 2012

Score: 110/110 with honors

Università degli studi di Torino - Computer Science Department

Master of Science: Computer Graphics, Virtual Reality and Multimedia Thesis: Visual Effects for Real-Time Stereoscopic Rendering

Università degli studi di Torino - Computer Science Department

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science (Networks)

Thesis: Spam Analysis tools

High School P. Gobetti

High School: Science

Thesis: Mathematics applied to 3D Computer Graphics Programming

KEY PROJECTS

₩ SEP, 2020 — JUL, 2021

 $\stackrel{\text{\tiny $f m$}}{=} D_{EC}$, 2019 — J_{AN} , 2020

₩ Nov, 2018 — MAR, 2019

\(\exists Dec., 2016 − Oct., 2017 \)

₩ APR, 2007 — JUL, 2009

Confidential project

- Technical direction, R&D, shaders, custom tools

Underwater VR — Oculus VR Experience

A VR experience in which you cruise aboard an underwater vehicle to explore some of the facilities of Italy's largest energy company.

- Unity, C#, HLSL, Volumetric effects, Caustics, Stereoscopic VFX

Skill Steal — PC (Prototype, Unreleased)

A multiplayer battle royale where opponents can steal each other's skills.

- Unity, HDRP, 500+ realtime lights in the same environment at 60 fps

Visual Effects for Real-Time Stereoscopic Rendering

(https://www.dropbox.com/s/3al2u9etsteaqcl/thesis_original.pdf?dl=0) — Master of Science Thesis

Some VFX are not suitable for VR because they alter the correct perception of depth. The thesis shows a possible solution for a kind of distortion VFX applied to 3D models.

Blind (https://store.steampowered.com/app/406860/Blind/) — Oculus, Steam VR, PSVR

Blind is a narrative-driven psychological thriller for virtual reality where the player is blind and must explore their surroundings using echolocation.

- Fully custom lighting system and shaders for echolocation
- Light management and optimisation algorithms built from scratch
- Stereoscopic VFX and post-processing
- Unity, C#, CG

Mathematics applied to 3D Computer Graphics (https://github.com/Chosko/high-school-thesis) — High School Thesis

A thesis regarding some notions of trigonometry and geometric transformations, which I studied while making my first graphics framework, and a 3D demo application showing the solar system.

- Made at the age of 16-19 with DirectX, C#, HLSL shaders

Other personal projects

More about other projects on LinkedIn, GitHub and my personal website

LANGUAGES

Italian Native speaker

English Professional working proficiency

Interests

Guitar: Electric Guitar, Classical Guitar **Puzzles:** Rubik's Cube and others